hello and good evening everyone I am
riddle Mishra from the corporate
communication in T and on behalf of
carriage I welcome you to our today's
discussion on non-life insurance ready
to take off and we sincerely appreciate
your time in joining us for this webinar
we would like to welcome steam gear
speakers for today we have with us Mr
Samir Shah executive director and Chief
Financial Officer is DFC a good General
Insurance
financial officer and chief risk officer
icci Lombard General insurance and Mr
Rajiv kumaraswamy managing director and
chief executive officer at magma SDI
General Insurance
the session will be moderated by Mr
Sanjay agarwal's senior directorate
Carriage ratings uh welcome in this
section with the presentation by Neha
kadian associate director H which will
be followed by a final discussion along
with the Q a session you can please post
any queries during a discussion also
May invite Neha to make a presentation
please thanks
thanks
good evening everyone I am
associate director at krh and today I'll
discuss about the ongoing Trends in the
Life Insurance not a life insurance
industry and output going forward
looks like synopsis
the health insurance segment given its
high contribution to the non-life
insurance sector will drive the
normalization of loss ratio
the claim payout has come down from the
peak levels witnessed during the
pandemic this along with increase in
pricing especially in the group health
insurance will further support the
premium growth
further increase in yields on debt
Investments considering the current
Rising interest rate environment will
drive the overall profitability for the
sector
improve technician to net worth along
with relaxed regulations to raise debt
and Equity will provide sufficient
growth Capital specially for the private
insurers in the medium term
further easing solvency requirements for
crop insurance will free up capital for
future growth for the entities with
sizable share in the crop insurance
Market
key regulations like removal of product
wise commission caps implementation of
use and file initiative proposed bhima
sugam platform are expected to further
optimize the distribution Network and
push the growth further
overall We Believe improving
profitability more access to growth
capital and increasing regulatory
support will boost growth for the
non-life insurance sector
next slide
we'll start with one of the key ratios
of the industry which is the Lost ratio
so non-life insurance industry you know
it's majorly driven by two major
segments health and motor with each
contributing more than 30 percent of the
gross direct premium of the entires
industry
in the health insurance segment the Lost
issue Peak during Financial year 22 due
to covet leg claims but moderated in H1
Financial year 23 with the easing impact
of pandemic this along with increased
pricing especially in the group health
insurance and Rising awareness has
helped the insurers to increase their
Top Line benefiting the loss ratio
the second largest segment motor
insurance reported steep decline in loss
ratio in financial year 21 due to covert
induced lockdown however the ratio
normalized in financially at 22 with
easing restriction on movement
while the pricing in third party motor
insurance is largely regulated High
competition exists in the own damage
segment which puts pressure on the
overall pricing in the motor insurance
industry
going forward we expect the loss ratio
in the motor segment to remain largely
in line with the past trends
the loss ratio in the crop insurance
segment which contributes to around
10-15 percent of gross type premium
return will continue to remain dependent
on weather conditions and thus May
remain volatile
for other segments we expect loss ratio
to be in line with the past Trends
subject to any external shocks
as can be seen from the graph on the
left side of the slide the overall loss
ratio for non-life insurers feed during
Financial year 22 to 92 percent due to
covet lead claims but moderated to 87
percent in H1 Financial year 23. the
Lost issue is expected to further reduce
to around 85 86 percent level going
forward
next slide
coming to the expenses part
the high customer acquisition cost
especially in the retail segment
continue to impact the expense ratio in
the non-life insurance industry
as deflected in the graph or the left
hand side of the slide expense ratio has
ranged between 29 to 33 in the past
it reduced to around 30 in financial
year 22 however again normalized to
around 33 percent H1 financially at 23.
going forward too we expect this ratio
to remain largely range bound
health insurance industry has relatively
High expense ratio as compared to other
segments due to its operational
intensive nature from the perspective of
claim management engagement with agency
Channel and workflow running with
network hospitals
the recent proposed regulations to
remove product wise cap on commission
rates and implementation of overall
limit on expenses of management to
around 30 for general insurers and 35
percent for health insurers is
considered positive for the industry
this will provide the insurers much the
flexibility to push key product segments
and to make required investments in the
distribution Network
that's right
even on investments will benefit from
the rising interest rate environment
so with consistent hiking report by
Reserve Bank of India to tame in
inflation the Elon debt Securities is
expected to improve
further the insurers have been Shifting
the portfolio to longer tenant
Securities as they end research speaking
of the current interest rate cycle
assuming the return on Equity to remain
largely in line with the recent past
Trends overall return on investment is
expected to increase to around 8.9
percent in financial year 23.
further favorable regulations on
increasing exposure to 81 Securities
rise in exposure limit to around 30 for
the overall vfsi industry increasing
investment in invertebrate and relaxed
dividend criteria for Equity investments
will further support the elite over the
medium term
increased availability of resources to
underwrite more risk
as can be seen from the graph on the
left private insurance with solvency
levels higher than 2x have sufficient
Capital required to achieve their target
growth
the public sector on the other hand
except for two entities they remain
entirely dependent on Equity infusion
from the government and Regulatory
forbearance to support the growth
to provide sufficient availability of
growth Capital the regulator has come up
with number of initiatives recently
the threshold limit as with the
pre-approval requirement today
subordinate debt has been waived off
Equity Investments are also expected to
get a boost considering relaxation in
the concentration and the minimum
promoter State threshold
also for the entities having sizable
crop insurance in their portfolio
solvency margins are expected to benefit
from the recent amendments in the
solvency margin calculations
all these measures along with the
expected Improvement in the
profitability profile will provide
additional growth capital
mix it
other growth drivers
low penetration levels along with
growing per capita income will continue
to provide steady demand for the
industry
India's Insurance penetration stands
quite low at around one percent
though it has been increasing
consistently from point seven percent in
financial year 2014 to around one
percent in financial year 22. it Still
Remains quite low compared to the world
average of around 4.1 percent
this low penetration level paves way for
the consistent growth in the insurance
sector in the long run
under its vision of insurance for all by
2047 have taken several initiatives
which are expected to further support
the industry growth in the long run
next slide
industry on the group trajectory with
gdpi expected to grow at double digits
so impacted by lockdowns during covet
the growth in Gross direct premium
income had slowed to single digit in
financial year 21. but it has rebounded
through increased demand for health in
financial year 22. this can be clearly
seen from the graph on the left
in The Current financial year the group
health insurance segment benefited from
rationalization of Premium discounts
medical inflation and enhanced coverage
while the retail Health segment growth
looks to be normalizing post the
pandemic
the government schemes have also
increased their share due to Iceman
Bharat scheme
with increased pricing along with Rising
awareness support the health insurance
motor insurance benefits from pickup in
automobile sales and increased Tariff of
third party motor insurance
stricter implementation under the motor
vehicle set will further support the
segment over medium to long term
driven by regulatory initiatives covered
above low penetration and increased per
capita income levels the non-life
insurance sector is expected to grow at
around 14 to 15 percent in financial
year 23.
next slide
favorable outlook for the non-life
insurance industry so going forward
gross type premium income is expected to
grow at around 13 to 15 percent over the
medium term driven by health and motor
insurance segment
coming to the profitability part driven
by the Improvement in the loss ratio
along with the rising yield on debt
Investments the overall profitability is
expected to improve for the sector
expense ratio is expected to remain
range Bound in the near term however the
new regulations and if the economies of
scale kicking in we expect it to improve
in the long run
overall private insurers are expected to
report report return on Equity of around
13 to 14 percent by the public insurers
profitability is expected to remain
muted
further uncertain geopolitical
environment High inflation rising cost
of capital it can negatively impact
economic growth and subsequently the
non-life insurance sector
thank you now we move onward to the
panel discussion
thank you Neha
a request to all the participants in
case you have any queries here please
requested to key in in your panel
he has over 24 years of experience in
the field of ratings Banking and infra
Finance prior to joining Carriage Mr
Agarwal worked at ICICI Bank and ifci he
has a bachelor's degree in Commerce a
grad CWA and a fellow members member of
icai is a qualified Financial Risk
manager from Gap USA and a certified
financial planner from fpsb India over
to you sir
uh thank you mridu and thank you Neha
for setting the context for these
discussions
so before we move ahead it's my pleasure
to introduce the extreme steam panelists
today
so let me start with the notice that the
speakers would provide views on the
industry as senior Executives of the
industry and as industry experts
hence this discussion should not be
construed as view the position of the
companies to which the speakers belong
again participants are requested to key
in the question in the space provided
uh can you begin with a slight trees
so let me introduce the participants now
Sameer Sameer Shahid PEB and CF of HBS
submit is the challenge content cost
accountant company security and has
pursued sisa from USA
he has reached experience of 31 years in
the field of finance and financial
services and 16 years in The General
insurance industry
he's been a part of the industry level
Committees of irida and ICI
of India
for his exceptional effort and
contribution to corporate finance he has
been presented the CF 400 role of
honored by CFO India for last seven
years
the company is DSC Ergo has been awarded
at the Excellence in financial reporting
for last seven out of 11 years from The
Institute of Chartered Accountants of
India
next please
office of ICC Lombard
the first general insurance company in
India to be ISO 9001-2035
gopal completed his charging company
courts in the year 1998 after completing
his CA code gopal worked in ICC Bank in
the corporate account and Taxation
department for two years
as its CFO gopal has that ICC member to
many achievement it was the first
general insurance company to be listed
in India
Award for best presented accounts for FY
2019 and FY 20. gopal himself has been a
winner in the ca CFO large BFS award
category of ICI in January 2021
yes please
is the MBA and CEO of magma HDI GIC
Rajiv is a fellow member of The
Institute of Charity Conference of India
and an associate member of The Institute
of cost accountants of India he started
his career as a banker and spent first
six years of his career in project of
presence corporate funding and Loan
restricting activities
he has been with the insurance industry
since its opening to the private sector
and has held positions of head corporate
center and chief risk office of ICC
longboard GIC and chief representative
of current SC India lies in office
respectively
Rajiv joined magma SDI GIC in June 2016
as its MD and CEO
so Netflix
so now we begin the questions the first
question is to Rajiv the regulatory
landscape has lived up with the arrival
of the new erida chairman
so what does your interaction with the
regulator or your views in the market
suggest on the regulator's vision and
methods of raising insurance penetration
in India
thank you Sanjay and thank you to the
entire Carriage team for having us as a
panelist
see if we look at the overall direction
of the regulator uh the Grand Vision is
at the end of The 100 Years of
independence of the country the intent
is to ensure that every corporate
citizen has a health insurance home
insurance motor insurance term insurance
you know accident insurance
so if you look at the broad cohorts in
which the regulator is working uh one is
the entire
platform on distribution
where their belief is that the current
ecosystem should have the benefit of
accessing greater number of Channel
partners and hence expanding the entire
Bank assurance and IMF distribution
architecture from the current three
Partners to nine Partners each
the second belief is that a country of
our size deserves to have more insurers
and hence opening up the entire
licensing regime and you would have seen
that there is this recent statement
there one new entity has been licensed
and there are almost 18 other on the
Anvil
as well as probably recognize the need
that there may be Niche players and
Niche segments who may come in uh like
what has happened say in the banking
space which is small Finance Banks so
they are looking at maybe micro
insurance companies looking at
Cooperative structures so the whole
ecosystem and the enabling regulatory
framework to allow the distribution
architecture to flourish
the second is the aspect in terms of
creating bandwidth for the industry to
come out with Innovative products
uh not have long waits to launch those
products
hand uh have a much larger enabling
environment from a Sandbox regulation
and also from a distribution
architecture promote the ensure Tech
related uh initiatives
the last pedest or the third pedestal
the way we look at it is uh look at
easing the compliance button for the
industry so that we focus on uh the
development part while yes they would
migrate to a risk-based governance
framework depending on the size of the
company so that's the Grand Design
and the last is if all the three
building blocks work the access to
capital for the industry is made easier
and hence uh the whole concept of
subordinated debt uh no prior approvals
expanding the uh enabling regulations to
ensure people have more access to
subdate as well as the access to private
Capital uh because earlier you know
there were a lot of the private markets
or the private Equity investors who had
a keen interest to come into the
ecosystem as investors however they did
not for whatever reason want to take on
the promoter obligation so there there
has been an alignment that up to 25
percent you can come in and still be
classified as a promoter with a
relaxation on the lock-in period
depending on the maturity of the
organization in terms of the age of the
organization uh
the overall approach is participative
it's a two-way dialogue and I think it's
a very very refreshing change as far as
the overall industry is concerned
yeah I think uh those are the keywords
that we change has been very refreshing
and pretty different from the way
Regulators were dealing with the
industry till now and the speed and the
innovativeness which I've made shown has
been pretty exemplary
so coming to Bhopal are there any risk
of disruption from insurance take
players especially in the non-life
segment given the non-pro sticky nature
of the non-line business
I think
thanks thanks Sanjay for having me on
this webinar uh and I think when you
look at the non-life insurance Market uh
as was initially introduced by Neha this
is a market which is significantly
underpinated uh you saw the penetration
levels over let's say two decades
increasing from point seven percent to
let's say one percent of GDP in terms of
gross revenues and despite that if you
see the extent of under penetration that
exists across segments of businesses is
pretty large I mean uh we can go on in
terms of the extent of underpredation
that exists having said that I think uh
obviously digitization is the way to go
in so far as development of the market
is concerned and when you talk of
digitization it just pass not across uh
sourcing of businesses it also kind of
spans across visiting of claims and
equally there is a need for every
institution or the sector to look at
digitization of their internal processes
as well
now that's where you would possibly get
to see a lot more competitive element
coming into the sector
now it's it's up to each of the
institutions to decide how do they want
to look at insured Tech as a key enabler
to doing business or you look at them as
one more competitor in the field
uh to my mind I think a lot of
institutechs are operating in platforms
or revenues which could act as
complementary in so far
as the growth of the money proved to be
of a great positive and equally is where
I think as I said uh individual
companies will have to also keep in mind
their own digitization Investments uh in
uh into into its requirement and
accordingly kind of make the right
Investments so I would obviously say
that the market has always been very
very competitive irrespective of whether
you talk about insure Tech or otherwise
in general the market has been
competitive as raj Chief mentioned with
more number of let's say players
entering The Fray entering the sector I
think the relative competitive intensity
could further get accelerated having
said that I think the discipline of
writing businesses keeping in mind
underwriting as a focus will what will
also determine how do you look at some
of this uh competitive elements so the
way we would look at is insure Tech is
definitely a partner to kind of work
with and look for capabilities in terms
of where they can bring a differential
experience and use it to the advantage
is the way I would kind of respond
thanks foreign
agencies or they can be your own company
where you use a lot of digitization and
technology for all the processes
means the market is competitive but I
think uh we're looking at other
Industries and how technology can move
out there so that's my next question for
Rajiv
so except for a few insure Tech gears
are not as large as the counterparts in
let's say the fintech segments
so what do you think are the key reasons
for the same and which kind of insure
take care of you think uh could become
more relevant let's say the aggregator
or the analytics provider or the niche
insurers or whatever
and uh do you think insurance as a
service I mean we say banking as a
service or do you think insurance as a
service could be available in the near
future given the regulator intent to
give much more licenses and all that
so I think the whole uh way we look at
it Sanjay is uh the understanding of the
public at large and the industry it's
large in terms of what is an inshore
Tech player vis-a-vis an evolved player
who has digitization as a core to their
platform or to their business right I
mean if you look at today uh most of the
insurance players uh have agent portals
where agents can issue policies with
customer information and every insurer
would have the ability to switch on
switch off underwriting filters and have
pricing at a district at a vehicle and
maybe even at an intermediary level so
the entire customer onboarding to my
mind is digitized it is a question of
how much people are probably positioning
their company as digitally enabled
players and as gopal rightly alluded to
your claims need to be digitized I if
you today do a scan of the market you
would find that let's say for motor as a
product class most of the companies
would have video streaming as a claims
payment uh facility which is
digitization at its core uh instant uh
survey assessments they would have AIML
tools for certain asset classes we know
some of the large players have
introduced AIML in terms of claim
assessment on the health insurance side
companies are introducing rpas to
automate their internal processes so
it's more the questioning of what is uh
in short Tech and I don't think we've
reached a stage where today the country
has a Geico or a UK direct line or an
entity of that scale which we can truly
call in short Tech uh I think customer
access customer kyc remains a challenge
and today given the way the market has
evolved I think the consumer at the end
still does rely on the agent
so it is more at least the way we look
at it is how
can you enable your partners to digitize
and ease the onboarding process but at
the same time be ready for the
disruption see I think disruption is
going to be a way of life and as bhupal
rightly said every company will need to
keep its cost structures very tight to
make sure that they remain competitive
in a world which is constantly going to
change
so that's the way we look at you know
the entire ensure Tech world uh at an
overall places but I'll be happy to hear
the others views on this
so Sameer would you like to add on to
this
right now
thank you uh to the care team uh and
thank you Sanjay and for inviting us to
be on the panel
um yes uh to a certain extent yes I
would also Echo the views of my
colleagues gopal and Rajiv that yes the
uh ensure Tech ecosystem uh in in our
business or in our industry will have to
coexist and I would say they would be
complementing uh all of us uh in in our
business the way we deliver our products
in the way we service our customers uh
and and it is becoming a kind of an
inevitable thing that one needs to have
it due to the size of the business that
we have the kind of operations we run uh
especially in our country which is you
know uh so large in terms of length and
breadth of the country
we definitely need insurance uh and this
technique technology you know to serve
our customers not only at acquisition
stage but also to service them
be it uh beat claims uh Journey or you
know be It Journey for buying the
products or or any other servicing needs
so I think you know it's a kind of a
necessity which is uh you know now
become for the scale and size of the
companies which we operate and hence uh
I think we all will have to coexist uh
in one form or rather
interesting observation thank you all
three of you are saying that uh you
actually welcome indirectly you're just
saying that you are almost welcome in
short take as a thing because it uh
provides a lot of support to the
complexity of the business and and the
companies themselves are ready in terms
of the technology and digitization from
end to end from the customer to the
Servicing
so interesting observation so changing
the uh there's now Sameera
uh the question we have is Indian
non-lifers have a very high combined
ratio both at an absolute level and
relative to let's say the large key
European economies or Emerging Markets
now is this mainly due to the extremely
competitive nature of the industry or
are they more factors at work
so with interested I think do you think
the competition will increase or will
the combined ratio be going up further
how do you see this whole trend
thank you Sanjay I think it's an
interesting question at this point of
the industry you know where where we are
looking at also uh inviting more players
into the market
uh I think and this is very interesting
question and on the first point of views
as to why why are the combined ratios
the higher compared to our peers in in
other economics and the competitiveness
I would say is there across the globe in
all the businesses including insurance
uh so I don't think you know uh the
competitiveness of the business in our
country is the only reason for you know
uh relatively higher combined ratios
that we have
um I would say you know there are a few
peculiarities that we have in our Indian
market today and which you know um
say I would not say justify or which uh
says that okay find the uh higher loss
ratios are fine for that matter
the first and foremost being the
accounting uh treatment that we give in
our country for the uh acquisition costs
so we don't have a dacking uh for that
matter
and hence to that extent our results are
also not directly comparable to our
peers in other economies in Europe and
other Imaging markets
and hence I would say you know that is
one factor which takes our you know
combined ratio uh a bit bit higher
second factor which impacts our combined
ratio is the uh the nature of our third
party business
uh the third party business as you are
aware you know aware the loss ratios do
develop over a period of time first of
all and after that the payment cycle
also is slightly longer and hence you
know the loss ratios in the third party
uh on an undiscounted basis are on a
higher side
and and that again you know is another
factor with day which takes our combined
ratios uh slightly uh higher and if I'm
not mistaken on some you know back up
the envelope calculations done
um because of the third party uh loss
ratios and and because of this concept I
think the combined ratios are higher by
you know around 300 to 400 business
points at minimum uh compared to other
economies
so this these two are the you know um
factors which I would say make are
combined ratios you know slightly uh
higher than other economies coming to uh
your other point on
um I think you you spoke about whether
you know uh the combined ratios you know
whether they are uh
yeah I think Rising interested
would be
yes so I would say uh in India uh again
you know looking only at the matrice of
you know combined ratio may not be uh
the only Factor one should you know look
at for you know evaluating any non-life
company
so combined ratio uh clubbed with the
written on
um Investments would be you know written
on Equity not Investments return on
Equity would be a right metrics that one
should look at
and both when both looked at together
you know it would really give uh um I
would say reasonably uh good uh
evaluation of the performance of a
company or the industry
uh so so return on Equity
um is is also you know quite comparable
when we look at or even better if you
ask me uh in if you look at it uh when
we compare it with the you know Western
World or over Emerging Markets you know
one because of uh the uh uh the uh I
would say the um investment multiple
that we have you know to our net worth
you know that that is one one factor
which helps us to get you know better
return on equity
uh and and
um the higher interest rates
um coupled with the uh better
um investment book multiple
um also helps us to get a good return on
Equity so yes so the meta is of combined
ratio is good for you know looking at
the operating visits when you look at
the underwriting results
when you look at it at a company level
uh return on Equity uh would be a good
indicator for you know
a non-life segment
okay
yeah so two points one I think is the
conversation in the industry on IFRS on
implementation of IFRS which probably
will take care of the accounting
treatment
that you discussed that probably some
amount of
difference would come up there internal
Equity even now look decently okay for
the industry as a whole I mean that's
what I have to presented
it's a good point so they're coming back
to Rajiv the regulate have been taking
several steps uh some of which you
animated earlier
management expenses
then as you said the number of tie of
the Distributors can have it insurance
so do you expect this to have structural
impact on the distribution Network and
do you see it impacting the growth of
the industry
so we will I mean this is something
which has just been notified uh
you know you have various
entities on the distribution Spectrum
who've taken uh completely contrarian
views right I mean you have Banks who
have just gone ahead with one tire and
they are happy with one tire
and there are entities who may have had
their own insurance entities but they've
still gone ahead and had three types
so it will remain to be seen how some of
the uh you know Partners view this
I think from a larger ecosystem uh while
I think the regulator has done a lot of
work to ease the compliance burden from
an insurance company point of view
I think there are if I may use the word
some pain points which still remain when
it comes to the corporate agents and the
bank Assurance tie up uh I think if
there is some work which is done to
reduce the compliance burden for
Distributors on that end of the spectrum
especially the banks who are coming in
as corporate agents I think then there
could be possibly a little more
explosion today at least as we see it uh
it is an opportunity but we will need to
be a little cautious and see how people
actually view this as an opportunity
so in terms of growth do you see any
impact
see the growth I think if you look at
the last five years cagr industry has
been growing at 15 if you look at the
current year 10 month number sorry eight
month number still November we continue
at 16 and a half so I think industry
doubling in every five years to my mind
is a given and uh I think the
opportunity the market itself presents
provides immense opportunity for growth
to come in I think distribution would be
an enabler to achieve those growth rates
but I think growth is something which we
can take as a given for the industry for
some times to come
oh
so coming to Bhopal how do you foresee
industry landscape to evolve considering
amendments to the insurance Act and the
IIT Act
like uh significant changes like
scrapping of minimum Capital allowing
different kind of features like captive
Insurance composite insurance which can
offer Life Health non-life all of them
so how do you see the industry landscape
to be changing with this
so that's a very difficult one Sanjay if
you will have to do a prediction of what
could happen right so having said that
uh I think let's look at what has
happened so far I mean historically if
you would have seen uh motor has by far
been the largest contributor to the
overall revenues for the in terms of
premiums however if you look at uh for
understandable reasons Health became by
far the largest segment in the year gone
by I mean for both reasons obviously
increased Awareness on health and
obviously motor had its own set of
challenges so
in terms of opportunity I think one sees
a lot of potential
across segments which are the existing
ones whether it is motor whether it is
Health whether it is across commercial
lines and increasingly when you look at
it in so far as the way forward is
concerned which is the original point
that I made the country is significantly
uh under penetrated uh and that can be
gouged by even the existing segments
where there are significant levels of
entrepenetration and even other segments
like let's say for example home
insurance
uh the point that Rajiv started off
initially with the vision of the
chairman uh hardly any percentage of
homes in the country is insured so
there's a significant runway for
growth and that could be a change that
the sector could actually experience
many of the matured markets
overall industry contribution uh in the
Indian market while retail liability is
taking off in some reasonable form uh so
far as corporate liability insurances
are concerned still it is not a very
large contribution in terms of the
aggregate numbers so that's an
opportunity that the market would see
provided we are also able to underrate
the risk adequately uh in terms of what
we retain on the net uh the third
element when you again specifically talk
in the context of Health
uh what you largely see in the market is
hospitalization insurances
a large part of the healthcare spends
two days out of pocket which is not
necessarily getting covered in a
meaningful form so that is what the
industry could largely expect in terms
of landscape changing we could see a lot
more offerings on the OPD Space by
various players in the market which
again can start becoming to add
meaningful contributions to the
continued accelerated growth that we
have seen on the health insurance
platforms that's an Avenue that one
would logically get to see in terms of
growth uh if you look at some of the
other point that you made Sanjay in
terms of uh freeing up let's say minimum
Capital requirements in terms of
allowing licenses for differentiated set
of players again the point that Rajiv
initially started off with the thinking
is pretty much on the similar lines is
what you see on the banking side you
have different types of banks which
logically caters to different lending
requirements uh in the insurance market
so far we have only been seeing largely
let's say a live or maybe a general and
a health you may possibly come across
players which are Niche Insurance
players where obviously one can expect
growth in those segments where they will
be operating with you could expect to
see players coming and possibly tapping
into increasing penetration for a
geography or a territory that could be a
change that one could kind of witness in
terms of changing landscape if you look
at The Regulators Vision itself they are
equally asking the existing
start looking at
looking increasing penetration in
certain jurisdictions or territories
that they want each of the companies to
own now that's a platform by which you
can actually start creating a
differential Edge so that's a changing
landscape that you would see
the enabling guidelines on Sandbox which
was an experimentation initiative to
bring about Innovative products already
we have seen the uh green signal being
given particularly on the motor side
with respect to the various sandbox
initiatives that can be now launched on
a commercial basis now that's a big
positive so that could actually kind of
change the traditional motor insurance
policy that one would have seen so far
so all in all I would say the landscape
of insurance
is uh and maybe the last point which I
have to also make is today insurance is
being looked at significantly as a risk
transfer mechanism I think going ahead
what you will also see which some of the
players in the market are exhibiting is
to see insurance companies as a risk
mitigation partner and therefore if they
are able to do a lot of value-added
services
which will actually kind of play a very
important role in let's say mitigating
or managing the risk of the entities
which is being underwritten and that and
that's again there is an enabling
regulation around that now this is all
areas which I would say across product
the distribution part I think anyways
Rajiv covered and some of the new
innovations that we are seeing is how
one would expect the landscape of the
market to evolve over whatever period
one is talking about
yeah I think are you pointing out to a
huge amount of potential across products
in within the existing products also and
probably Niche products like the
the the
contractor Assurance uh the one which
was launched recently by Bajaj Allianz
so probably some of the rich transferred
this mitigation products out there
so coming to Sami the Diversified
non-life players have not been able to
match up pace with Eastern stand on the
Shahi player in terms of growth and
product innovation
so what do you think expensive dichotomy
and how do you how would private spread
periods be able to how do they intend to
beat the gap
which could be profitable given that the
covet is behind us
yeah so uh Sanjay I I get you us what
you're saying is in terms of the growth
of the Diversified General insurance
companies and when we compare it with
the Standalone health insurance
companies
so uh when we when we look at the
um matured uh General insurance
companies uh for that matter
so uh in in then then I think the growth
rate
um when if we look at it and we compare
that with the base of the Standalone
health insurance company so uh I think
that we will have to you know keep in
mind when we compare the growth rate of
you know both in terms of you know uh
kind of maturity of both the companies
the size of the both the type of the
companies is also involved
so that is one secondly the Diversified
General insurance companies are
concerned they operate in in the all
these segments uh which are impacted by
the growth of uh General
macroeconomic and government in the
country
and hence they do serve the larger
segment of the economy and yes to the to
certain extent they would also reflect
the uh growth in the economy in those
segments also
uh Standalone health insurance companies
yes they only uh reflect the health
insurance uh
segment part of it and which yes in
these times uh has been in uh you know
uh Limelight and the growths have been
you know uh in upwards of 30 or 35
percent for that matter
so I think to that extent when we
compare the growths of both the you know
uh segments I think we will have to keep
this factor in mind
uh another element which I observed that
you were making were in terms of the
innovation
uh aspect so when we look at the um
health insurance products I think these
are most of these products are you know
standardized products the kind of
offerings which needs to be given has
also been you know specified by the
regulator in terms of uh what kind of
coverages are required uh so so in terms
of Indemnity products I would say 90
percent uh just to you know give a ball
part number uh of the offerings are the
standardized products and hence the
Innovation would only come in terms of
add-ons which are uh offered offered by
these companies
and I think in terms of uh the companies
which are you know
um Diversified companies they are also
you know providing Innovative you know
products uh for that matter
so in terms of uh
the product features yes there could be
you know something more which can be
done and uh but but I would say that 90
of the offerings would remain consistent
coming to Innovation more than the
Innovative products or the you know
terms of the coverages which are there I
would say the differentiation will only
come in the way uh the customers are uh
treated the kind of uh servicing which
is done and The Innovation would more uh
probably come come on that that segment
and that is where Diversified Insurance
companies are also not behind and More
in terms of you know how the customers
can access the products of the insurance
companies how they can you know uh buy
the products how they can compare the
products and even how the servicing is
done once the claims are uh registered
by these customers and whether whether
they are able to uh track these claims
more more specifically in terms of
health claims when you know I think
the customers are more in need of you
know the settlement at uh you know fast
pace and what kind of you know uh
treatment they get at the time of claims
so I would say I know uh the promises
which the insurance companies make you
know the moment of truth comes only when
the claim is there and hence I would say
Innovation would more uh be required uh
in terms of you know servicing and you
know when the claimant really needs the
insurance company the most
yeah so uh for that matter just to give
an example of the product that we have
launched your road Optima secure
and there I can tell you that you know
the Innovation which one looks at
everything one can find in that product
and in the first year of launch itself
we could see uh customers you know
taking taking that up and over over uh
100 crores of Premium was done in less
than a year I would say in eight or nine
months
so uh I would say uh that you know
Diversified companies are also you know
uh up there uh on the curve and
servicing would be more important if you
ask me you know then then the product
features
okay so you you're saying that it could
probably be just a moment of time it's
one particular asset or the
classification is under greater
Limelight so hence the players Niche
player shift catering to that segment
probably have their own uh have the
moment in the spotlight but divertified
players are throughout all classes for
all opportunities
correct so now we move on to Rajiv
the growth momentum in the domestic
automobile sales has picked up was
pandemic and then along with the
increase in the third party motor
insurance studies has supported the
growth premium in this first eight
months of this year
however did a lot of competition in the
own damage sector so how do you think
this road train will pan out and
what do you think would be the last
ratio given the pricing constraint that
area
it's an interesting question Sanjay I
think the profitability pressures have
always remained on motor
and if you dovetail what is likely to
happen in motor which say The Regulators
intent with new licenses to come in uh
there is a natural tendency for the
newer players to gravitate towards
writing motor business because that's
cash flow business and hence the
profitability pressures will be there
uh having said that uh I think there are
a couple of things which from an
ecosystem have been uh created which
have helped you know companies also get
persistency on the motorcycle with
regard to TP which is on the two wheeler
business as well as the private car with
the regulator launch the OnePlus 3 and
the OnePlus 5. uh if you would have seen
the working committee report there is a
Direction Where We can even on the
renewal portfolio look at providing some
long-term products but I think I would
just like to give a word of caution
there that uh as Samir alluded to what
we are taught in class 11 and 12 that
you match your expenses with your
Revenue Unfortunately The General
insurance industry doesn't fall follow
that you know forget about the uh you
know long-term products it's not even
applicable on annual products so the
accounting charge on long-term products
would be far far more significant and
just to give you a sense if you look at
March
the industry was sitting on almost 65 to
70 000 crores of UPR on which all costs
are incurred and I'm not even getting
into advanced premium on long-term
products which the industry is probably
sitting on this accounting anomaly is
something I think the regulator will
need to look at very seriously with
enabling changes in taxation rules
having said that I think companies have
the ability to analyze their own
portfolio when it comes to own damage
uh you've typically got a tail of 24
months so even if you look at some of
the new age companies who've been in
existence say for a decade compared to
say some of the larger players who've
been in existence for 20 years people on
OD would have the ability to price
products far more Discerning with than
TP
the other thing which is happening from
a structural change is if you look at
say five years back say 2017 the odtp
mix was queued more towards OD
today if you look at it the skew is more
towards TP in the industry is probably
less than 40 percent OD and sixty
percent and up towards TP where I think
reserving certainty is increasing and in
a rising interest rate regime while
there remains are reserving volatility
but it gives you the advantage of float
so if you look at at an overall level uh
the industry on about 1 lakh crore of
capital that has been deployed about
four lakh crores of investment book
which is the float that Sameer had
talked about
whereas if you look at the same kind of
float on health companies the float will
be much lesser because Health companies
have a much shorter tail
so for them the combined ratio will
become important so you cannot afford to
run your book on high combined ratios
you need to necessarily have range bound
combined ratios because you don't have
the benefit of thing
but uh to answer your question I think
competitive intensity on motor has been
there it will continue to be remaining
there
figure
about 18 percent 18 000 crores of uh
let's say cost pre-booked
again at the industry level that would
be about 15 to 20 percent of the
addition to the net worth of the
industry
so interesting conservation I think if
the regulator is able to address this
rather than the solvency relief that has
been given on crop and the subject
this one change will release far more
capital for the industry than all these
changes put together
so the again the noise on bringing IFRS
into the account
so there's a question for sameen that uh
currently the uh the shareholding is
largely with through equities take by
the promoter but with the thing of the
non-read discussed in terms of bringing
in external investors 26 percent and all
that
uh so can we expect the insurance to go
for more interest to go for listing how
do how do you see the landscape
thank you Sanjay I think it's an
interesting question and very topical uh
in in recent times uh so
I think past few years I think we have
seen insurance industry uh undergoing
some kind of a consolidation
foreign
we we lost you for some time you're a
new type now we'll ask you for something
hello yeah yeah sorry sorry I think I
think there was some some technical
issue uh so so what I was saying is that
recently uh the amendment which I
proposed uh by the regulator in terms of
allowing promoters to go up to 26 for
the listed and uh 50 for unlisted
and allowing investors to go up to 25 uh
singly and jointly up to 50 I think this
changes you know would really you know
ease up the accessibility of capital for
for the companies and definitely you
know this is a kind of a nudge which the
regulator is making to the companies to
get listed
uh like like you would have seen in efsi
also once the uh nbfc series a
particular scale uh I think they and
they get a consistency of results you
know they they do get listed
and in terms of uh General insurance
companies at least I could say that now
over two decades the industry has
matured enough and the companies have
also realized you know what kind of
models to work and what kind of models
are required you know uh to be in the
business for long term and for
consistent results
so I think you know this is the uh right
time for uh the insurance Industries to
you know get into different kind of
investors and uh also you know get
listed
and I see as a trend you know uh that
you know over over next you know couple
of years
uh we would see you know large number of
uh investors coming in the Indian market
considering the kind of uh potential
that the industry also offers
um again going back to
um uh what gopal said in terms of the uh
penetration of you know about one
percent uh and also out of pocket
expenses on the health side being around
you know 55 percent of the total spend
government spending also being around
three percent of the total you know
allocation so I think all these factors
you know uh do bring into Forefront the
potential of the industry and hence the
attractiveness for the investors uh
and and once once the companies are
listed I would say it would bring in
more you know a discipline governance uh
uh to the industry and hence I think the
vision of uh the regulator and the new
chairman is I think absolutely uh dot on
and I know this would bring in a lot of
respect also for the industry if you ask
me
uh so uh I see that you know apart from
you know the top uh GI company uh top uh
GI company top uh public sector company
uh and a top reinsurance company being
listed uh and and also the health
insurance company being listed I think
that's uh just a beginning and I we
would see a lot of more companies
getting listed in the times to come
okay so you're saying it's the right
time to get listed and there's already
precedence in the market in terms of the
way the investors could value them and
understand them
the threshold on reading equity and uh
debt from the investors have been
relaxed
so what Quantum of capital do you expect
to be raised by non-life companies
so uh Sanjay that's an interesting point
I think uh the way I would kind of
respond to it is uh I mean if you look
at the uh regulatory minimum on solvency
let's say it's 1.5 times now if you look
at uh the industry as a whole
uh obviously Kobe did a share of its own
impact on this solvency numbers as well
uh the industry was slightly operating
pre-covered the year before at an
aggregate solvency of roughly about 2
10. now that number if you see for fi 22
has actually come down to about 1.7
times all there about so obviously kovit
had its own share of losses on the
solvency as well having said that I
think if you look at the overall market
and I'm talking about for let's say over
last uh 14-year cycle
this is from the time the industry was
deregulated from tariff from 2008 until
the while the point that Sameer also
made and Rajiv also made the industry
has grown reasonably well at a
compounded rate in Top Line of almost
over let's say 15 16 thereabout
however if you see the relative outcome
in terms of underwriting
the combined issues have actually got
far more deteriorated I mean it was
close to about 112 percent way back in
that number at the end of FY 22 was 119
percent
of course as I said Kobe would have had
its own share of losses but even let's
say the year one year before that
the industry combined in f521 deposit
roughly about 113 percent of that
records effectively no change in
Combined even after 14 years of let's
say the market durability from tariff
that speaks of couple of impacts because
one is you get growth Capital through
incremental investment coming in from
various classes of investors there is
internal generation
so to my mind it has to be a combination
of both while what the regulator has
done is obviously kind of enabling far
more access for companies to be able to
raise capital in times of need but what
is more important is for companies to
seriously look at
driving businesses or underwriting
businesses far more profitably
that would by itself generate the
necessary growth Capital which will help
them to cost possibly start becoming far
more self-sustaining
uh so that's the way I would kind of
look at while the change in the extent
of norms for raising capital
has been changed but just as a thumb
rule if you look at for every let's say
100 rupees of business that and the
industry has to write roughly you need a
capital of close to about 25 rupees so
it's one by four now now you can put a
number in terms of whatever growth that
one is expecting as Rajiv mentioned this
industry is rightfully poised to at
least grow in the range of 15 to 20
percent over the foreseeable term uh
which is what they have the industry has
demonstrated over the last so many years
and therefore corresponding to that the
growth the requirement of capital would
arise which will be a combination of
both the change in the regulation that
has been brought about by the regulator
and more importantly I would say the
internal self-sustaining surpluses that
companies will start to will need to
start to kind of deliver so that that's
the kind of capital requirement that the
market is expected
oh yeah
I don't know so something probably you
can also take this question we are
having it from the audience
uh what what sort of demand do we see
from Life Insurance segment in the bond
market in fy24
but in the debt Market borrowing demand
from the life insurance sector in fy24
uh
just to understand the question better I
think
uh this is the uh Demand on the bond
market in terms of the debt uh
investment side Equity the subordinated
yeah I think uh the uh kind of uh
relaxation which the regulator has given
uh for for the subordinated debt uh and
and the way the way it is panning out
now I would say the kind of capacity
that has been created through this
relaxation is equal to the amount which
was already there so uh the the uh I
think the um capacity of the general
insurer to borrow by way of capital has
increased two-fold
and and this is really going to give a
huge boost to the uh solvency for this
sector
but yes caveat the caveat is that you
know one needs to be really profitable
uh after payment of uh
the interest and dividend
so one will not be able to pay interest
uh if one is not making profits
so uh that will have to be looked at you
know only the companies who are able to
make profits uh uh will be able to you
know raise uh the capital as earlier
also
but yes it has increased the
accessibility and hence definitely the
bond market would see the more supply of
uh the non-life uh Bonds in the market
for that matter
okay
so do you have any number on what is the
outstanding date
uh not not really uh Sanjay at least I
can't get it immediately uh
has been approving uh
it means for the interesting dividend
even in cases of losses so they
subordinate that all these preference
Capital with the companies have raised
now the data has allowed the companies
to go in for those instruments without
seeking its approval yeah but in case of
our loss they still have to take the
approach from the data so do you think
that structure will change where as of
now only solventy was looked into and
then the
approvals have been given but now that
uh they did not take the approval while
raising the debts who they want the
company to be more responsible
uh definitely Sanjay I think as I said
that requirement was earlier also there
that the approvals were required
if if the you know companies were not
making profits and they still wanted to
distribute interest and dividend
so yes uh so this all all uh the reforms
which the regulator has undertaken are
in the direction of news of doing
business that is for the companies to
raise you know Tire to Capital uh and
and who have capacity to service them
secondly uh they this will also
strengthen the companies in the times to
come and this will help the companies to
even you know grow faster uh the
deserving companies will be able to you
know deploy capital in a right direction
and to write more businesses and thereby
increase the penetration of influence in
the country and thirdly uh by asking
approval from the regulator for
Distributing interest where they are
loss making they are also taking care of
the interest of the policyholders
and hence I would say you know um the
regulator is working you know uh 360
degree in all the direction One
strangling the company's uh ensuring
penetration and also ensuring the policy
holder protection so I would say this is
again a win-win for you know a right
kind of companies
yeah
so I think we already overshot so I just
take three short questions
what do you think would be the headline
growth in the net insurance premium for
the industry for the next uh
55 years
would put pegate at 15 to 20 at the same
level which gopal also mentioned okay
and gopal what do you think would be a
reasonable estimate for industry as a
whole internal
term go again for the next two to five
years
so Sanjay the way I would kind of put it
is I would kind of not necessarily do
crystal gazing on loss ratios I think I
would say that the industry needs to get
as I said more disciplined on combined
if the industry as a whole is able to
operate and get the combined better from
the current levels of 119 that to my
mind I'll give you a great positive in
the long term structural growth for the
market
okay
and uh Samir what do you think is a
reasonable Landing estimate followings
for the next two to five years again
yes so Roe is I would say you know post
tax could be anywhere in a ballpark of
20 percent
20 20 yes so 15 to 20 percent is the Roe
you know Target that uh
a matured uh General insurance companies
can you know definitely achieve
look so great gentlemen uh this was a
very informative session we have many
questions from the pan from the audience
but probably who is directed to one of
you I mean a couple of questions to each
one of you and get the answer and then
respond to the respondents
and I think that the way because we
already showed the time by six minutes
and uh we I think that we've been time
to now wind up so thank you very much
for uh joining us out here in this panel
and we thank the audience for patiently
going through the proceedings and now we
I'll transfer this back to Middle to
take it down
thank you sir uh thank you for
moderating this session and thank you
Neha for the presentation and to all our
guest speakers for the insightful views
Mr Shah Mr balchandran Mr kumaraswamy it
was a privilege to host you and thank
you to all the participants for taking a
time out and being a part of this care
ratings webinar uh we look forward to
your feedback suggestion in the feedback
Meal which will be coming no sooner the
webinar ends thank you and goodbye Tech
Team to log off please